Richard Murray Research Material Regarding Abbott Handerson Thayer
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Research Files, 1948-2004, Series 2:; (Box 2-8; 6.1 linear feet)
  - Research on Specific Works of Art (Box 6)
    - Portrait of the Artist's Son, Freer Gallery of Art, 1992-1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Portrait of Beatrice, Everson Museum of Art, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Portrait of Beatrice Holden, Addison Gallery, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Portriat of Bessie Price, Willard G. Clark, 1993-1998 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Portrait of Elise Dufour, circa 1990s (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Portriat of Jennie Remington, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Portrait of Joe Evans, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Portrait of Kate Bloede Thayer, Sewell C. Biggs Museum of American Art, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Portrait of a Lady, Cincinnati Art Museum (Deaccessioned), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Portrait of a Lady, Freer Gallery of Art, circa 1992-1997 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Portrait of a Lady (Miss Bessie Stillman), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Portrait of a Lady (Mrs. William B. Cabot), National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Portrait of Raphael Welles Pumpelly, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Portrait of Richard T. Fisher, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Portrait of a Woman (Miss Gertrude Bloede), National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Portrait of a Young Girl, Rhode Island School of Design, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Prize Bull, Freer Gallery of Art, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Red Flamingoes, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Roseate Spoonbill/Roseate Spoonbills, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Roses, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Roses, Vance Jordan Fine Arts, 1997, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Seascape, Vanderbilt University, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - Seated Angel, Wadsworth Atheneum, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Self-Portrait, Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Self-Portrait, Hirshhorn Museum, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Self-Portrait, Charles M. Plunket, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Self-Portrait, Metcalf/Mauran, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - Self-Portrait, Allen Blagden, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - Self-Portrait, Cleveland Museum of Art, 1993, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - Self-Portrait, National Academy of Design, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Self-Portrait, Snite Museum of Art, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - Self-Portrait, National Portrait Gallery, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Self-Portrait, Babcock Galleries, 1993-2000 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - Self-Portrait, Chesterwood, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Self-Portrait (Drawing), Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - The Sisters, Brooklyn Museum, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - The Sky Simulated by Red Flamingoes/White Flamingoes, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - Sleep, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Sparrow Perched Among Clover and Daisies, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Sphinx Caterpillar, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Spring Hillside, Thomas Rosse, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Standing Woman, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Stevenson Memorial, National Museum of American Art, 1997-1999, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Still Life, Indianapolis Museum of Art, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Still Life - Game, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Still Life with Bowl of Roses, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Study for Boy and Angel, Dayton Art Institute, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Study for Caritas, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Study for Seated Angel, Hirshhorn Museum, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Study of Old Woman, Brigham Young University, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Sunrise on Mt. Monadnock, New Hampshire, Princeton University, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Sunrise, San Remo, Charles M. Plunket, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - The Three Graces, circa 1998 (Box 7, Folder 83)
    - Townsend Bradley Martin, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 84)
    - Unidentified Portrait, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 85)
    - View of Dublin Pond, New Hampshire, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 86)
    - Village Street, Dominica, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - The Virgin, Freer Gallery of Art, circa 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 88)
    - Virgin Enthroned, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997, (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 89)
    - Waterlilies, Dicke Collection, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - West Indies, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 92)
    - White Flamingoes, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 7, Folder 93)
    - William M. S. Stillman, Brooklyn Museum, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 94)
    - Winged Figure, Art Institute of Chicago, 1997-2001 (Box 7, Folder 95)
    - Winged Figure (Angel), Fogg Art Museum, circa 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - Winged Figure, Freer Gallery of Art (1911), circa 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Winged Figure, Freer Gallery of Art (1918), circa 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Winged Figure Seated Upon a Rock, Freer Gallery of Art, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Winter Dawn on Monadnock, Freer Gallery of Art, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Winter, Monadnock, National Museum of American Art, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Winter Landscape, National Academy of Design, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Winter Scene, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Winter Sunrise, Monadnock, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Winter Through the Window, Addison Gallery, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Woman in Grecian Gown, Addison Gallery, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Woman in Green Velvet, Addison Gallery, circa 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Woman in White Dress (Alma Wollerman), 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Young Girl, Chesterwood, circa 1997 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Young Woman, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1997-2003 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Young Woman in White, Addison Gallery, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Photographic Materials, 1961, circa 1990s-2001, Series 3:; (Box 8-9; 1.7 linear feet)
  Found here are photographs of Thayer, his family, friends, studio, house, as well as photographs of his artwork. Also found are negatives, color transparencies, and slides of these photographs. Of note are photographs of a Thayer exhibition at the Lyman Allyn Museum and photographs of x-rays of Thayer paintings.
  Researchers should note that all photographs of Thayer, his family, house, studio, and artwork are copy prints of original photographs which Richard Murray requested from the owners for his research. Most of the original photographs of Thayer and his family can be found in archival collections at the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.
  Photographs are arranged by subject. Negatives and transparencies are also arranged by subject, but slides are arranged in no particular order.
  - Photographs of Abbott Thayer, Family, Friends, circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 16-18)
  - Photographs of Thayer Studio, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Thayer House, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of New Hampshire Landscapes, circa 1990s, (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 21-24)
  - Photographs of the J. L. Smith House, circa 2000 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Exhibition Photographs, Lyman Allyn Museum, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of Archival Documents, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Painting X-Rays, circa 1990s (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Artwork (Box 8)
    - Drawings, circa 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 29-30)
    - Ideal Figures, circa 1990s, (6 folders) (Box 8, Folder 31-36)
    - Landscapes, circa 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
    - Nature, circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 39-41)
    - Portraits, circa 1990s, (3 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Self-Portraits, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - At Addison Gallery, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - At Freer Gallery of Art, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Comparisons (Artwork by Others), circa 2001 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Negatives and Transparencies (Box 9)
    - Abbott Thayer, Family, Friends, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Archival Documents, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Drawings, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Ideal Figures, circa 1990s, (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 12-13)
    - Landscapes, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Nature, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Portraits, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Self-Portraits, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1990s (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Slides, circa 1990s, (5 folders) (Box 9, Folder 19-23)